<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>PORTFOLIO on SALMA AZZOUZI</title>
    <link>/portfolio/</link>
    <description>Recent content in PORTFOLIO on SALMA AZZOUZI</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 02 Jan 2022 19:47:09 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/portfolio/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Dimensionality Reduction LDA&amp;PCA</title>
      <link>/portfolio/pca-lda/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Jan 2022 19:47:09 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/portfolio/pca-lda/</guid>
      <description>A higher number of dimensions theoretically allows for more information to be stored, but in practice it is rarely useful because of the increased possibility of noise and redundancy in real-world data. Thus, several methods have been developed to perform dimension reduction. In this work, I present two linear dimension reduction methods, namely: Principal component analysis, and linear discriminant analysis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learned and optimized Communications</title>
      <link>/portfolio/loc/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Jan 2022 19:47:09 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/portfolio/loc/</guid>
      <description>The main issue in communications is ensuring a reliable transfer of data. In order to do so, many channels and system models have been implemented with tractable mathematical models. In this regard, AFF3CT is a library that is used to implement the physical layer of most current and future standards (WiFi, 4G, 5G &amp;hellip;). Today’s communication systems have been thoroughly optimized making them very efficient and stable. Introducing deep learning into such systems may not be as efficient in communications as it is in other fields such as speech recognition and computer vision.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mosaic Project</title>
      <link>/portfolio/mosaique/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Nov 2021 19:47:09 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/portfolio/mosaique/</guid>
      <description>An image mosaic is the combination of several images having a part in common in order to reconstruct a panoramic and unified view so that objects representing the same structures are superimposed. These images can be observed from different angles. The construction of a mosaic requires first the conversion of the images into triples (I,M,B).
The second step is the estimation of the geometrical transformation between the spaces of the different images Homography.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ADS-B Project</title>
      <link>/portfolio/adsb/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Sep 2021 19:47:09 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/portfolio/adsb/</guid>
      <description>Automatic Dependent Surveillance–Broadcast (ADS-B) is implemented in air traffic systems as a complement to conventional radar. It allows the aircraft to estimate their positions thanks to GPS technology. These signals are then picked up by the antennas. The objective of this project is to process these signals in order to decode and display their content and to simulate in real time the ADS-B transmitter/receiver. For more detail, please check the Githyb link above.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Power of Deep Learning for Channel Estimation and Signal Detection in OFDM Systems</title>
      <link>/portfolio/docteur-ing/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jun 2021 19:47:09 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/portfolio/docteur-ing/</guid>
      <description>I am a laureate of the engineer-doctor course of my school. This experience introduced me to the field of research through the exercise of thematic bibliographic study of papers. My tutor Mr. Romain Tajan and I were working on the approach of exploiting deep learning to handle wireless OFDM channels in an end-to-end manner.
The simulation results show that the deep learning method has advantages when wireless channels are complicated by serious distortion and interference, which proves that DNNs have the ability to remember and analyze complicated characteristics of wirless channel.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MICA Project</title>
      <link>/portfolio/sample-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Mar 2021 19:47:09 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/portfolio/sample-project/</guid>
      <description>The main goals of the project were visualizing electrocardiogram (ECG: test that detects and records the strength and timing of cardiac electrical activity) to analyze the spectrium and then using Pan and Tompkins algorithm to detect the QRS complexes that allow us to detect cardiac pathologies. See Github link above for more details about the code and the report.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DSM Project</title>
      <link>/portfolio/dsm/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2019 19:47:09 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/portfolio/dsm/</guid>
      <description>This project aims to develop a shared and distributed memory system on networked machines. It is divided into two phases, the first of which aims to develop a program launcher, which has the task of launching different processes on remote machines via SSH, while retrieving and centralizing the standard and error outputs of these machines. This first program also sets up everything necessary for the DSM in the next step, such as setting up listening sockets leading to an interconnection of all processes between them.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
